<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<RelativeLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:app="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:background="@drawable/download1"
    tools:context=".PronunciationGuides">

    <TextView
        android:id="@+id/titleTextView"
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:gravity="center"
        android:text="Lesson 1: English Word Pronunciation"
        android:textSize="30sp"
        android:textStyle="bold" />

    <ScrollView
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="match_parent"
        android:layout_below="@id/titleTextView">

        <LinearLayout
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:background="@drawable/images23"
            android:orientation="vertical">

            <!-- Lesson 1 paragraph -->
            <TextView
                android:layout_width="match_parent"
                android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                android:text="Many people who discover how to learn English as a second language come up against a very frustrating problem! They study hard to be able to speak with correct grammar, accurate vocabulary, and relevant expressions. Yet when they speak, they still sometimes hear responses like:\n\n“I’m sorry, what?”\n\n“Could you repeat that, please?”\n\nIt’s extremely annoying! If your English pronunciation isn’t good, then your level of fluency will be consistently underestimated. A strong accent can be a great barrier to making connections. Research even shows that employers in the US often favor candidates who speak with standard versions of British and American accents for more prestigious roles.\n\nOne thing is for sure: working on your pronunciation skills is definitely worth the effort. Read on for eight effective strategies to help you sound like a local, and a few expert tips from our friend, the YouTube teaching star, Bob the Canadian. Here’s a quick overview:\n\nHow to improve pronunciation\n\n1. Focus on phonemes\n2. Search YouTube for tips from fellow learners\n3. Try some tongue twisters\n4. Learn new words with their pronunciations\n5. Read aloud and record yourself\n6. Listen to some podcasts\n7. Speak slowly\n8. Spend more time talking to native speakers\n\n8 proven ways to improve your English pronunciation\n\n1. Focus on phonemes\nIt can be helpful to go back to basics and examine the sounds used in English words. This doesn’t mean singing the alphabet again — you probably learned that a long time ago! It means learning the English phonemes.\n\nWhat are phonemes? Well, you may have noticed that many letters are pronounced differently on their own than when they are used in words. Many letters contain more than one sound – “F” for instance is pronounced “e fff”. Phonemes are the smallest unit of sound in the English language — the sounds that letters contain when broken down. This video is a great introduction to what these sound like.\n\n2. Search YouTube for tips from fellow learners\nThere are some difficult sounds that are pretty unique to English, and pronouncing them will be difficult for non-native speakers. As Bob the Canadian mentioned, your native language might not have helped you develop the muscles necessary to make these different sounds. The good news is that you aren’t alone in this!\n\nWhichever letter combinations, phrases or words you are struggling with, other language learners with your native language have struggled with them too!\n\nTry searching on YouTube for “English Pronunciation Tips for [your native language] Speakers”. There will almost certainly be a number of tutorials from students who have found a way around your problem. In all likelihood, there are teachable exercises that helped them progress.\n\n                3. Try some tongue twisters\nIf you can’t make the sounds you need to in order to pronounce English words, then you might need to give your mouth and tongue muscles a workout. One great way to improve your English skills is with pronunciation exercises like 'tongue twisters' — silly sentences that are extremely hard to pronounce on the first try.\n\n4. Learn new words with their pronunciations\nIf you’re practicing vocabulary and come across a word that you have no idea how to pronounce, do not try to guess. It is far easier to learn the correct pronunciation from the beginning than to fix a bad habit later on. Look words up for free on a site such as:\n\nDictionary.com if you are learning an American English accent.\nDictionary.cambridge.org if you are learning a British English accent.\n\nIf you find a word particularly difficult to pronounce, you can even try recording the correct pronunciation on your phone to listen back to later.\n\n5. Read aloud and record yourself.\nAs Bob the Canadian mentioned, it can be very helpful to record yourself on your phone when practicing pronunciation. Identify a word you usually struggle with, and find a TV show, movie, or YouTube video where a native speaker uses it in a sentence. Listen to the pronunciation a few times, and then record yourself speaking it. Some people also find it helpful to practice in front of a mirror, where you can check to make sure the shape of your mouth and lips are correct.\n\nPlay both back, listen carefully for what needs correcting, and try again. Repeat the exercise until you are happy with how the phrase sounds. It’s boring work, but thoroughly working through difficult words is a step towards perfect pronunciation!\n\n6. Listen to some podcasts\nListening skills are also critical for learning pronunciation of a new language: you need to listen to native speakers and pick up on their speech patterns. Podcasts are great for getting familiar with English as it is really spoken. They are often recorded by people in bedrooms and studies, speaking to their friends in a completely natural way. Some applications and websites, like YouTube, enable you to listen at half-speed, which is a great way to really focus on the sounds you are hearing and understand the accents in detail.\n\n7. Speak slowly\nWhen you have pinpointed which sounds you need to work on, and taken steps to change the shape of your mouth or tongue as necessary when they come up, you have done most of the 'thinking' involved in changing your accent. Now, it comes down to learning to make the new sounds automatically – replacing your old speaking habits with new ones.\n\nThis phase will be easier if you slow down your usual pace of conversation, giving yourself extra time to think about the new rules you have learned. Whilst speaking slower will probably be a bit frustrating, giving yourself time to consciously choose the more accurate pronunciations you have studied makes them more likely to stick in the long term.\n\nAccording to some researchers, it takes around about two months for a new habit to become automatic – which is not a long time to wait to see serious results!\n\n8. Spend more time talking to native speakers\nBy far the most effective way to minimize your accent in a foreign language is to talk to native speakers. Think about it: how often have you found yourself picking up a friend’s speech patterns or slang, completely without trying?\n\nIt can really help to ask your English-speaking friend directly about your accent. They can pinpoint which words you pronounce differently and help you identify mistakes that you can’t hear yourself. In particular, word stress within sentences tends to differ between languages. Work with your partner to establish some key sounds to improve, and ask them to correct you if you slip up.\n\nFinal Thoughts\nThere are plenty of ways to work on your accent from home using videos, podcasts, and music, but there’s no substitute for talking to a fluent or native speaker!\n\nTry sessions with a Preply tutor, or discover the Preply Business English language training for employees, and you’ll be amazed at how quickly your accent improves. With 1-on-1 lessons, you can focus on exactly the skills you want to work on, like good pronunciation. A tutor will give you feedback on which words you need to practice and recommend exercises specifically for you. With helpful feedback and a little practice, you’ll be speaking like a native in no time at all! Good luck with your language learning!" />



        </LinearLayout>
    </ScrollView>

</RelativeLayout>
